[WIND WHISTLING]
[CAMERAMAN] Quiet on
the set. And we're rolling.
[PENGUIN 1] Cody
Maverick interview, take one.
[CODY] So why are you
guys here to interview me?
[INTERVIEWER] It's what
we do. We're a reality film crew.
Should I know some of the
questions before we start?
- Just so I don't...
- No. Just, you know...
- They're, they're easy.
- Okay.
- Can you stand on that box, right there, please?
- Oh, yeah.
Just stand up on that thing.
- Ah, thank you...
- Right there? Whoa, what's the...
What is that?
[INTERVIEWER] It's a
sound thing. It's a microphone.
What's up, man?
I'm Cody.
[INTERVIEWER] And
you're what, 14, 15 years old?
Uh, 17 years of age.
And any other skills
besides surfing?
Like, like what?
Like singing and dancing?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- [LAUGHS]
No, not me, man.
I just surf.
- [PENGUIN] Loser.
- I just... Ugh!
Cut it out, Glen.
Stop, man.
[INTERVIEWER] You know, we're
here to make a movie about Cody.
- Does he have to be here?
- Yeah, it's gonna be great.
Can I get in line now
to not see it?
[INTERVIEWER]
We'll re-slate.
Since we're talking
about surfing,
- Yeah.
- why don't you give us your thoughts about surfing?
Surfing. Surfing.
[SUCKS LIPS]
Where do I start?
[INTERVIEWER] How about
just at the beginning?
Okay, well, uh...
So as soon as
there was the first wave, right?
There was the first surfer.
All they needed was,
like, a, um...
You know, something like,
some piece of driftwood,
a block of ice
or something like that.
And then they were off.
And they were hooked, man.
They were hooked.
Up till recent times,
you had your old dudes.
You know, your,
your hang-six cats.
These old guys used to lay down
with these huge,
humongous boards.
And these guys
were the pioneers,
but nobody saw
what surfing could really be,
until Big Z did it.
[INTERVIEWER] Could
you tell us who Big Z was?
[CODY]
Who was Big Z?
You're asking the right guy.
You got, you got that far.
Z is, heh, everything.
Big Z is surfing, man.
I mean, he's...
There may well as not have been
an ocean before Z.
They invented the ocean for him.
He lived so hard 'cause
he wasn't afraid to live.
He wasn't afraid to die.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
He came to Antarctica
when I was just a kid.
Man, it was just, whew.
It was the biggest thing
that ever happened here.
Then suddenly there he was.
Just...
floating over the water,
just hovering, you know,
like weightless.
Could've walked up to anyone.
And...
he walks right up to me.
And he gives me this awesome,
one-of-a-kind Big Z necklace.
And then he tells me,
"You know, kid,
"you know, never give up.
"Find a way,
'cause that's what winners do."
He was the greatest.
Everyone looked up to him,
respected him, loved him.
And one day,
one day
I'm gonna be just like him.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
And I've been surfing
ever since I can remember.
It's just hard to imagine
any part of my life
when I wasn't surfing.
I wanna get outta here,
you know,
and this is my ticket out.
I'm really good, man.
[SCREAMS]
I'm the best on the island.
[SCOFFS] I know it sounds
cocky for saying that, but...
I mean, I am, like...
[SCREAMING]
...the best.
[GRUNTS]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[CODY] Yeah, I was, I was born
and raised here in Shiverpool.
Lived here my whole life.
That's where they sort the fish.
It's the dumbest thing
I've ever heard of.
But yeah, I, I worked there
just to kinda pacify my mom
a little bit.
Good old Shiverpool.
[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
[CHUCKLES]
This place sucks, bro. Oh!
[YIDDISH ACCENT] I worked
my way up from the sardine pile,
- uh, then to the mackerel pile.
- In his day.
And I ended up
on the gefilte fish pile.
- In my day.
- All hard work.
Not like some's I could mention.
Yes, this farkakte kid
with the thing on the water.
My house?
It's down over there.
You see it right there
with the surfboards?
Yeah, I mean
I just live here with me
and my brother Glen, my mom.
He was a little, teeny,
small egg. Uh...
He wasn't very impressive.
Glen was the big egg,
Cody was the small egg.
He can't help it. He's...
That's just the way he is.
I mean, he's out there
in the water all day.
[PENGUIN]
All day.
You know, shirking
his responsibilities.
[PENGUIN]
Yeah, shirking.
You know, hatching these eggs
is a big responsibility.
[PENGUIN]
It sounds like it.
And my brother Cody,
he just doesn't understand that.
- Mm-hmm.
- He needs to...
step up and be a man.
It takes a real man
to sit on an egg.
Oh, you know it.
Quincy, come to Daddy.
He wants to be different.
All the time with the different.
Who's got the time in the day...
- [YELPS]
- Only six months in a day.
- [INTERVIEWER] Thanks for making it.
- Yeah, sorry.
- Thanks for making it.
- Yeah, how was it out there?
He's the big brother.
I'm the little brother.
I'm not touching you.
- Not gonna touch you.
- Do you see this?
- Don't. Get... Please?
- I'm not.
He makes sure
that I know that too.
[CODY]
I had to fight for everything.
I mean, even Mom's
tuna casserole, you know.
[HUMMING]
[BOTH GRUNT]
Yeah, here we go.
[GAGS]
[COUGHS]
[CODY]
I'm lucky I survived.
It really wasn't that easy
for him growing up.
Like I said before, uh...
he never, he never
really knew his father.
[CODY] I'm not really
the person to ask about it,
truthfully, 'cause I was just
too young to remember.
I mean... Look, I'm not
the only kid on the island
whose dad was, you know...
eaten.
[INTERVIEWER]
Still, it had to be traumatic.
No. Not for me, bro.
Not for me.
[INTERVIEWER]
What's your dream?
To go, uh, a-away.
To go away.
That's, that's, That's great.
Do you guys want a drink?
Gotta run away
from responsibility and life.
They don't want a drink.
This is kind of...
This is unique.
This is, this is not the norm.
[MOCKINGLY]
"I have dreams."
[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
When is this not happening?
What...
Don't make that noise.
[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
- Cody!
- It's really disrespectful.
[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
- I would never do that.
- Mm-hmm.
You just wouldn't make it
out of your mouth.
That's the difference
between you and me.
You know what?
I can't do this anymore.
Mom...
Look what you did.
This is for me.
This isn't for you.
Why is Glen still here?
Oh, yeah, exactly. Mom!
[SLOW MUSIC PLAYING]
[CODY] I don't understand why
everybody has to be so judgmental.
I understand
why Mom's judgmental.
I think it's 'cause
she cares partially.
I think it's also partially 'cause
everyone else is looking at her like,
"Hey, Cody's just a bum.
"Cody's this. Cody's that.
Cody's this."
Cody's me, bro.
Let me be me.
When is that gonna start?
[PENGUIN] You know what
they call me? The dream maker.
The dream maker.
I find these kids,
I bring them here,
and I give them a chance
to be somebody.
You know, my greatest joy
as a surf promoter? Finding Z.
Watching him rise to the top.
I still can't believe he's gone.
He was like a son to me,
you know.
It was a heart thing, you know.
It was a heart...
[TEARFULLY]
Can we just take five minutes?
How's my hair?
Is it messed up?
I ain't got all day.
Shut up. Is it mussed?
[INTERVIEWER] We just have
more questions about Big Z.
Right now I think
we're more interested
in telling
the Reggie Belafonte story,
and who could blame us?
But Big Z is kind of
the focus of our...
Hey! Let's get the
coconut-filler guy over here.
And how about the guy
sweeping the sand?
Can we hear your boring story
about your tedious,
ridiculous life?
Hm? Me?
Get your feathers off it!
Stop! Stop!
I ain't got all day. I got
a big production here, okay?
Roll, okay? Just roll!
[ANNOUNCER] Welcome, fans,
to another edition of SPEN Sports.
This is Sal Masekela,
and we're here at the
surfing capital of the world,
Pen Gu Island,
for a preview
of the tenth annual
Big Z Memorial Surf Off.
Professional surfers
extraordinaire Kelly and Rob,
tell us what kind of challenges
our surfers are going to face.
Well, first things first, Sal,
the wave.
It's the perfect combination
of beauty and danger.
Even the pros
are terrified of this place.
[PENGUIN]
Whoo!
[CROWD GASPS]
Hi, Mom!
Dig this, Sal.
Section behind me.
It's called "The Boneyards."
Very few surfers have ventured
in there and come out alive.
[SAL] Are you trying to tell
me people have died here?
That's right, Sal.
[SAL]
A moment of silence for them.
And we keep it moving!
Because if the Boneyards
was not enough,
our surfers will be
facing off with
Tank "The Shredder" Evans.
Tank, nine-time defending champ.
[GRUNTS]
A role model? No.
But I do consider myself
somebody that everyone
should look up to.
Kids should try to, uh,
pretend that they're Tank.
I mean, they should try.
[SCOFFS]
Good luck, kids.
[INTERVIEWER]
You never wanna get in there...
and help 'em out,
show 'em how to surf...
[WHIMPERING]
and spend time with the kids?
No, no, I don't wanna do that.
Anyway, this is my wave.
[SAL]
Always classy, Tank Evans.
Coming up after the break,
penguin dodge ball.
Stick around.
Okay, to get back
to the competition,
I just wanna say, uh,
I'm scouring the globe
for the next big thing.
Ow, oh.
But that's another story.
[MIKE] He doesn't look
for them. I find them.
I find these penguins.
I find the talent.
Reggie, uh, my boss, has sent me
literally everywhere
on this trip.
Any place there's an ocean,
a lake, a puddle.
It's ridiculous.
I am on so much
migraine medication,
you have no idea.
The stress is killing me.
I don't know how much longer
I can last.
I have to tell you that
right now.
[YELPS]
Whoa.
You gotta try
this blowhole thing, man.
This whale dude
is giving me a brain freeze.
I, uh...
I lost a bet.
Whoo!
Excuse me.
Does anybody in this entire
frozen wasteland surf?
Ah, the Cody Maverick kid
does that.
Wonderful, thank you. You know
you're sitting on thin ice.
[ICE CRACKS]
Oi!
Excuse me,
I'm looking for, uh...
I'm looking for Cody Maverick.
Has anyone seen Cody Maverick?
I'm, I'm Cody Maverick.
[GRUNTS]
[MIKE] Holy... Mike Abromowitz
from the Big Z Memorial
Surf-Off, Pen Gu Island.
You came here on a wha...
You came to see me. Wow!
Quite a slip-and-slider,
aren't ya?
[CHUCKLING]
You're here. I...
What an honor, sir.
I'm honestly so honored.
Lovely, wonderful.
So I hear you, uh, surf.
- Is this true?
- You gotta see what I can do.
- You can actually stand on a board?
- Please. I'll be right back.
You'll see what I can do, be happy,
everything'll be good, and I'm coming with you.
I can't imagine a better day.
[LAUGHING]
Ma! Ma.
Ma, he came... The scout.
Mikey. He came. He's here.
- What? Yeah.
- He's giving me a shot now, Ma.
- Okay.
- You wanna come watch me surf, mom?
- No, no, that's okay.
- Just this time.
I'm busy.
I'm chopping here.
Okay. All right,
well, wish me luck.
Cody, just be careful
of those big waves. Mm-mmm.
Well?
Anytime now.
You know, you... You should
have been here yesterday.
We had a sweet swell yesterday.
I mean, I was doing
some layback 360s and floaters.
- It was insane.
- Wow! Start the whale.
No! No, no, no. Wait! Wait!
Just give me one more chance.
- All I need is one, please.
- You just had it.
- Dude, please don't go.
- Tough break, kid.
- Just wait one second.
- Better luck next year. Move it.
- Let's go. He's coming. Let's go.
- One wave. That's all I need.
- Let's go.
- Please.
[CODY] I never, you know,
won anything my whole life.
You know, just once
I wanna feel like a winner.
You know,
I used to scout songbirds.
Toucans for this musical revue
in Brazil.
Now that's show business.
Toucans...
[CODY]
Hold on!
I don't care what you say,
I'm coming to Pen Gu!
No way, no how.
This is a contest
for big-wave surfers.
Can't this blubber ball
go any faster?
Step on it, fish sticks!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
[PENGUIN]
Is he all right?
[MEN CHATTERING]
Oh, poor kid.
I feel bad a little bit.
Honestly, this is embar...
[CODY]
No, wait! Wait!
[GRUNTS]
[PANTING]
[MEN CHATTERING]
[CODY YELLS]
[PENGUIN] Did you guys see
that? He almost had my board.
He almost had it. Oh, next
time. Next time we'll get it.
Yeah, so anyway...
- [CODY] Wait!
- [YELPS]
[GASPING]
[GRUNTING]
[MEN CHATTERING]
[PENGUIN GRUNTING]
We got you. We got you.
Oh, you are heavier
than you look.
Whoo! Man, we did it.
- Oh, thank you.
- Teamwork always pays off.
I'm Chicken Joe, man.
Oh, thanks, Joe.
Don't you ever, ever
do anything like that
in the contest, all right?
- I'm in?
- Yeah, you're in.
'Cause that was entertaining
in a horrifying sort of way.
[ALL CHATTERING]
- Right on, dude.
- Yeah.
My name's Cody Maverick,
Shiverpool. You?
No, I'm not from Shiverpool.
Oh. Where are you from?
Dude, I'm from Lake Michigan.
That's where I surf.
I was the only one
around my town who did it.
And uh, a lot of people
thought I was crazy,
but I'm used to that.
I know how you feel, Joe.
- You do?
- Yeah.
Radical.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Butt freeze! Whoo.
Somebody help the chicken.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
[LAUGHS]
- [SCREAMS]
- Look out!
Ha!
Slater, Machado.
How's it goin', bros?
- Goin' good. Thanks.
- What's up, buddy?
Okay.
Later, dudes.
Radical.
[ALL GRUNTING]
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
[CODY LAUGHING] Dude, look,
look where I'm standing.
I'm standing where Z stood.
[LAUGHS]
Aw, man. Aw, man.
Dude, you gotta try this.
No, I'm, I'm okay.
Come on.
Just one bite.
All right.
One bite, that's it.
Yeah, yeah?
What do you think?
I mean, it's not bad.
It kind of tastes like chick...
- Yep. What's chi... Chi...
- Chi...
[GIRL]
Coming through!
Oh, crap.
Can't believe
he'd do this to me.
[GIRL PANTING]
Oh, man.
I'm in love.
Help me! I'm drowning!
[COUGHING]
Then what're you standing here
next to me for?
Go talk to her, man.
No, I'm not gonna talk to her.
- She's digging on you.
- Joe.
- She called you crap.
- Thanks again.
- All right, well,
this is the third time you've
been unconscious this week.
I just don't think
it's very good for your brain.
- I know. Bye, Lani.
- Okay.
Joe, j-j-j...
Yeah, that was awesome how
you, uh, saved his life and all.
That was just...
unbelievable, ahem, really.
- [CHUCKLES]
- Yeah.
You here for the surf contest?
Uh, mm-hmm.
Well, I'll be watching you.
Really?
You'll be watching me?
Well, yeah,
from the lifeguard station.
- Oh, yeah. No, yeah. Yeah. Right.
- It's my, it's my job.
That's your job.
Hey, are you gonna kiss her
or what? What's going on?
- [GIGGLES]
- Come on, Joe. We gotta...
Dude, you said you were in love.
- I didn't say that.
- All right, look. He really digs you.
- Joe, listen to me.
- [LANI GIGGLES]
- He likes you, though. See ya.
- Shhh!
[LANI] Yeah, I love my job.
I have an amazing job.
Just this week, with the contest
coming up and all,
it's a little crazy.
You really have to be
extra, extra attentive.
When you have so many guys
in the water,
you can't miss a thing.
But you know what?
I have a perfect record.
I've never lost anybody.
Sure, there have been
close calls, but...
[WHIMPERING]
Help!
Oh, Arnold.
I turn my back for one...
Just lay some feeling on her.
- How do you mean?
- You know, through words.
- Through touch.
- Walk me through the approach.
I'm Lani. You're me.
You sure about that?
I get real serious.
Let's not. Let's not.
- Whoa.
- What is it?
That's it.
That's Big Z's shrine.
Remember?
[JOE]
Ye... No, no. Not really.
[ANNOUNCER] Today, the world
of surfing lost one of its legends.
Big Z took his final ride
this morning
during a competition
with up-and-coming surfer,
Tank Evans.
Z was last seen paddling into
a massive swell off Pen Gu Bay.
Friends of Big Z gathered
to remember and celebrate
his life.
- [THUD]
- [TANK] Great shot.
- [CODY] What? Hey!
- [TANK] Yes.
Oh. Every time.
He's got a pretty good
throwing fin.
Hey, stop doing... Hey.
Stop it! Cut it out!
That's like three in a row.
Here, give it a shot.
[GRUNTS]
Hey!
What? Wait a minute.
[LAUGHING]
Look at this.
Don't.
- It's a Big Z necklace.
- Stop. Stop it.
- That's not funny. Stop.
- [LAUGHING]
Hey! No, no, no. Stop.
What are you doing?
[TANK] Look, everybody,
it's Big Z's last fan.
[REGGIE] Coming through.
Outta the way. Let's go.
- You don't deserve to talk about him.
- He's a big zero.
- Shut your mouth.
- Zero starts with Z.
You'll never be
as good as Big Z, Stank.
[CROWD GASPS]
[JOE]
Hey, hey, people.
Come on now.
Smile on your brother.
Keep your girlfriend
out of this!
Hey, whoa.
You can't do that to my friend.
[GRUNTING]
Wow, I'm getting
quite a workout there.
No, that feels good.
Hey, why don't you work
on my glutes a little bit?
Ooh, that's very nice.
[YELPS]
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! All right.
- What?
That's enough, guys.
Come on.
I'll take you on
any time, anywhere!
Oh, well, then how about
right here, right now, huh?
- Hey, Mikey, Mikey!
- What?
Get this kid a board.
All right, who wants to see
the little guy take on the champ?
- [CROWD CHEERS]
- Little guys rule!
[REGGIE]
A little one-on-one
surfing action
between Tank Evans
- and... Jerry...
- [MIKE GRUNTING]
Cody. Cody.
[GASPS]
Cody Maverick.
Cody Mavencourt.
And the one that rides
the biggest wave wins!
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
- [INTERVIEWER] Are you nervous about
going against Tank Evans? - [CODY] What?
[CODY]
What? Ah, Tank. Nervous?
What do I have
to be nervous about?
Yeah.
[PANTING]
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
- Give it up! Come on, now!
- [CROWD CHEERS]
I'm gonna chum the water
with your head.
Bring it on, pecker face.
Let's go.
Pecker face?
[BOTH]
It's mine!
[INTERVIEWER] So, Cody,
when you take your first wave
and the whole island's
there to watch,
what's it gonna be like?
[CODY]
It's gonna be amazing.
Honestly, it'll be
the best wave of my life.
And I hope the cameras
are rolling
'cause you're gonna
wanna watch it over
and over and over
and over again.
It's gonna be awesome!
[SCREAMS]
[CROWD GROANS]
I can't look.
Poor kid.
He's... Poor kid.
Wow!
That was spectacular!
Whoa!
I'm number one, the Tank!
[GASPS]
[CROWD GASPING]
[PENGUIN]
Watch out!
[GASPING]
[GASPS]
[WATER SPLASHES]
[ROB] We're trying to get the
details, trying to figure it out.
The lifeguard
just pulled him in.
[CROWD MURMURING]
[ROB] That's what happens
when you take on the Tank, right?
[GRUNTING]
Cody! Cody!
How is he? Is he okay?
- What can I do?
- Yeah, he's okay.
I can help though.
Except if there's blood.
[BOY]
Mommy, is he okay?
Just the thought of blood
makes, makes me...
[GROANS]
Can somebody help the chicken?
- [HUMMING]
- Tank, you okay?
- Tank needs fuel.
- [YELPS]
Mikey, get the board, will you?
[TANK]
Blah! Tastes like sh...
Come on, okay.
Come on. Come on.
[COUGHS]
[PENGUIN]
Is he safe?
[CROWD CHATTERING]
Did I win?
I won, huh?
You should've stayed
in Antarctica, kid.
Oh, wow.
- You're gonna be okay.
- Look at that.
There's pixies everywhere.
[GROANS]
[INTERVIEWER] What do
you guys think about Cody
going into a contest
and possibly winning?
- You know, I'm...
- Ha.
Why did you just laugh?
'Cause he keeps
saying "possible."
Like it's "possible"
that you're gonna win.
And like you're
gonna do anything.
- I mean, really, what are the chances?
- Well...
They're high.
Aren't they high?
- [WHISTLING]
- I mean, they're normal chances.
It's not like
I'm like the underdog.
[IMITATES EXPLOSION]
[THUNDER CRASHING]
[GRUNTS]
[LANI]
Hey! Geek!
Geek!
Geek, get up and help me.
[GRUNTS]
[SNORING]
Geek.
Geek!
- Oh!
- Wake up.
- I need your help.
- Lani.
Come on. Get off your lazy butt
and come and help me.
Havin' this beautiful dream.
Okay.
Did you ever know Sheila?
No. I don't
know Sheila.
Wait, wait, wait.
What? What?
- What?
- Who's this guy?
He's... a surfer.
He's hurt.
Who are all those guys?
They're with him.
Ignore them.
- Come on.
- Lani, what are you doing?
If you help him,
they'll go away.
- Hey! Get outta here!
- Okay.
- [PENGUIN]Whoa!
- [LANI] Help him!
[LANI]
Where do you want him?
Nowhere.
That's the whole point.
No outsiders, Lani.
Come on.
- I know, I know, I know.
- [SIGHS]
This is an emergency.
He went down bad over the falls.
I don't know if he, If he...
[SIGHS]
[SCOFFS]
- And did he hit the reef?
- I don't know.
I'm not sure. He got...
I got him after...
Is he your boyfriend, huh?
No. No.
Why would you say...
Wait, wait, wait. Oh.
Looks like he stepped on
a fire urchin.
Stepped on me? Stepped on me?
Are you kiddin'?
This guy was dancin' on me.
I mean, just look at this.
Broken, broken, gone, gone,
broken, broken, broken...
This is... This is pretty bad.
This... This is...
This is really bad.
Ow! Ow!
- What... Cody!
- I hurt.
You're gonna be okay.
- Oh!
- What?
Maybe I shouldn't
have taken that out.
Uh, poison's released.
Wow, amazing.
What's amazing?
That you're still alive.
It's all right though.
I'm gonna fix you up.
I... I can fix your foot
just fine. Just, uh...
Where? Where is it?
Ah, I've been looking
all over for this.
It's a saw!
You just drew a saw!
Don't let him move like that.
He's... He's pushing the poison
all over his body.
[CLEAVER THUDS]
Come on, come on, come on.
- I know he looks...
- [GRUNTS]
Here it is.
[WHISTLING]
[LANI]
What are you doing?
What is he doing?
This is a sure-fire cure.
I learned it from
an old medicine man.
It, uh...
It, well, works wonders.
[CODY]
What is he...
What? No, not that.
Not what?
What is he gonna what?
Ah. Come on, now.
- Geek, stop.
- Let's do this.
Lani, can you make
some water sounds?
This is so gross.
- What is water...
- Shhh...
Ah, come on. Here we go.
No, no, no. You...
- [SQUISH]
- [SIGHS]
[CODY SCREAMING]
- Ow!
- Kid, you better keep your mouth shut.
See, what'd I tell you?
- Hold his foot still, Lani.
- All right.
Knock him out or something.
I'm running on empty here.
I'm trying! Ah!
[SIGHS]
So...
how you been?
[INTERVIEWER]
Wow, sea urchin in the foot.
That sounds pretty nasty.
Yeah.
How do you cure something
like that?
You pee on it.
[ALL GIGGLING]
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, that's disgusting.
I know!
Hey.
How long am I stuck
with this guy?
- Till...
- 'Cause, you know, I...
Till he's better.
Well, come back soon and...
please, bring me some clams.
- No. No.
- Lani, I'm running low here.
I can't keep doing this.
You gotta start
taking care of yourself.
- I... Oh, come on.
- Bye.
Bring me some more clams!
Okay!
[MURMURS]
[BURPS]
If it's just as well with you,
I don't wanna talk about Cody.
He lost. That's it.
That's his problem, not mine.
Aren't you concerned
about anybody's well-being?
The kid's fine.
He was born in water.
He's a penguin,
for crying out loud!
Did you see that wave hit him?
Yeah, dude, that's the
whole idea of surfing.
You know, I care. I care!
Mikey! Wait till
you see this.
Look at those little legs.
Tick, tick, ticky. Tick, ticky.
It's the way I walk.
And I'm constantly...
Boom-chicka-chicka.
Boom-chicka-chick...
What's with
the "boom-chicka-boom"?
[JOE]
I can't stand blood.
I can't stand
the sight of blood.
I can't stand...
sight of blood.
Cody!
Dude, have you seen
my friend, Cody?
- Mm-mmm.
- No.
Cody?
[GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
He's not under there.
Cody!
[ECHOING]
How's it goin', man?
Yeah, so I woke up this morning.
You know,
I didn't know where I was.
And it's never like, a good
place to be when you wake up.
[CHUCKLES]
You know?
Come on. Get up.
[GROANS]
I don't want to.
Breakfast.
Wakey, wakey.
Come on.
I don't want to.
Ow.
- How's your foot?
- My foot?
My foot's fine, but my head...
Good, good, good.
Come on, kid. Get up.
What the...
[SNIFFS]
Ooh!
Yeah, I think I got
a concussion.
Ah!
Sheesh.
You know, you should meet
my brother, Glen.
You guys would really
hit it off.
Oh. No, no, no.
Where's my necklace?
Did you see my necklace?
It's gotta be...
[SIGHS]
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Ah, big deal.
Get yourself another one
at Reggie's trinket shops.
No, it's not just some
necklace, guy. All right?
He gave it to me himself.
- Who?
- Big Z.
When he came to Shiverpool.
You know, that guy believed
in me when no one else did.
He told me never to give up
and to find a way
'cause that's what winners do.
Yeah, what winners do.
yeah.
It's just... It's funny.
You know, what a loser I became.
Who... cares
what Big Z said?
You gotta... just...
you know,
do things your own way.
I don't, you know,
I don't have a way.
Ah, well, you do now.
Just follow this.
It'll take you back
to North Beach.
Okay, Nice to meet you.
Good luck.
[SLOW SONG PLAYING]
[CODY]
What do I do now? You know?
I can't show my face
on the beach.
I can't go home.
[CODY] You always visualize
where you're gonna be,
what you're gonna do.
[CODY]
This ain't it.
Ah.
[CHUCKLES]
What are you doin' here?
- Here.
- [GASPS]
Oh, man.
Thank you, man. This...
Yeah.
That's really cool of you
to come back, man. Thank you.
Better keep that knot tight.
You lose it during a contest,
it's a goner.
Yeah, well, I'm not going
in any surf contests.
Ah, well...
there's more to surfing
than beating...
Tank Evans, you know.
- [SIGHS]
- Yeah.
Ha, look at that.
You know what
you're sitting on there?
Huh.
That's koa wood.
Best surfboards in the world
are made of that stuff.
Yeah?
You got a koa board?
No, I don't have
a "board" board.
Ah, well...
you wanna, uh...
You wanna make one?
Nah.
What?
Man, I come all the way back
here to give you the necklace,
and now I'm offering to make you
a board, and you say, "Nah"?
- I just...
- Get off your lazy butt.
- We're making a board. Come on.
- All right. Okay.
Gonna be the best board you
ever had, I'll tell you that.
- Then, okay. Okay, man.
- All right?
Cody.
[ANIMAL ROARS]
That's cool.
[INTERVIEWER]
Joe, can you just tell us
why you're out here
looking for Cody?
You know, we've known
each other way back
since, like yesterday,
I think it was.
We got a lot in common.
I never really knew
my father either.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Okay, so why are you
making surfboards
in the middle
of the jungle anyway?
I'm just trying to understand.
I don't get it, you know.
Kid, forget the 20 questions.
Let's just get
the board made, hm?
Okay, it's just...
Are you a surfer, or do you...
I mean, what are you...
[GRUNTS]
[GEEK CHUCKLING]
Ha-ha. Very funny.
Less talk, more
pushing, come on.
Why are we pushing it?
Why don't we just roll it?
- Because... Ow!
- [CRUNCH]
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it...
I didn't know
your foot was there.
Are you okay? I'm sorry.
- [CRUNCH]
- Ow!
I'm sorry. It's not like
I intentionally did it, okay.
- I'm sorry.
- Hey, whoa!
[GEEK]
Hey!
- Cody, Cody, the log.
- Yeah, I know!
Wait for...
Geek! Stop, stop!
- Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop!
- Cody!
Cody, grab the vine.
Grab, grab the vine!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
[GRUNTING]
Now, pull it.
I'm trying!
Pull!
[GRUNTING]
Ah! Cody!
[SCREAMS]
Geek!
Cody!
[GEEK SCREAMING]
Geek!
[THUD]
Oh. Oh, no, no, no,
no, no, no.
[GASPS]
[BOTH SIGH]
Help me up, so...
So I can kick your butt.
[LAUGHS]
Let's go.
I thought you... I thought I
killed you. I didn't... You okay?
Next time, when I say
don't roll the...
No, no. Wha...
Hey, what's that? What's that?
Yeah, it's a beach.
Sand, water, sun.
You seen one, you seen them all.
Come on.
Let's get outta here.
No, no, come on, man.
Let's go check it out.
- [CRUNCH]
- Ow!
[YELLS]
[GEEK GRUNTING]
[INTERVIEWER] So you think
Cody and the Geek are doing all right?
Yeah, yeah I hate to see him
living out there all alone.
It'll be good for him
to have something to do.
[GEEK GRUNTING]
Hey. Somebody's
old board shack.
Look at this.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
These are Big Z's boards.
Yeah, these are Big Z's boards.
He rode this
in the Australian Open.
[LAUGHING]
This is the board he rode
when he came to Shiverpool, man.
This, I-I ca...
Geek!
This is Big Z's place, man.
This is where he lived!
This is where
he made his boards!
Did you know this was here?
Why didn't you wanna
come down here?
[CODY]
And then he, uh...
He went up
to this old shack, you know.
[PLAYS PEACEFUL RIFF]
And...
I realized, you know...
it was Z.
I could tell
he needed some space
and, you know,
some time to himself.
I didn't wanna, you know,
ask him all these questions,
so... just kind of
stood there quietly.
You're Big Z!
[LAUGHING]
I can't believe it.
You're alive!
That's the respectful way to go,
I think.
Why are you alive?
What happened?
Tell me.
Tell me everything.
Start at the beginning
and just go. Tell me.
- Kid, kid! You'll hurt yourself. Relax.
- Yeah.
But you were dead. Right?
And people said you were dead.
But you're not dead,
you're in hiding. Ha!
Did something happen? Something
happened. You saw something.
You saw something
you weren't supposed to see.
I knew it!
That's what happened!
What, are you nuts? It's not
a conspiracy. It's no big deal.
Oh, what happened?
I don't wanna talk about it.
Okay, you don't...
Okay, I got it.
I'll be over here
if you need anything,
or, you know, you just feel like
talking, or, you know, whatever.
Do you feel it now?
Like talking now?
Go away.
Got it. All right.
I'm going away. I'm go...
Unless, I mean, you...
- Cody!
- Okay, got it. Okay.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
This is, like, you know...
It's huge, man.
It changes everything.
It's like it, you know...
The contest is a few days away.
If I can get him to train me,
then that's...
Boom.
I mean,
I could win this with him.
It... I mean, it's my dream,
you know.
And I don't wanna
give up on that dream.
Winners, winners find a way,
no matter what, right?
Mm, a winner is...
- Mmm!
- Um...
They see their goals.
They just go for it.
They're not in it
for the money or the glory.
A winner is...
- Oh! Hey!
- Like...
Hey, hey!
It's the surfer who's out there
having the most fun.
Yep, it's a lot of fun.
Right, no, I get you.
What's winning
without the losers?
They're in it for the joy of it
and the rapture,
and the slow-motion
instant replay, which is my...
Mikey, why don't you
head over to the snack bar,
and get yourself
a big bowl of shut up?
Feels better when there's
a lot of losers around.
Was, was that your question?
Well, a winner is somebody
who doesn't knock me
off my surfboard...
break it when I'm trying
to get some big waves.
Especially Tank.
He is definitely not a winner.
He's a dirty trash can
full of poop.
Yeah, I can't...
I can't remember a time
when I wasn't surfing.
My mom put me right on there.
I think she pooped me out,
just put me right on there.
[INTERVIEWER] What is it
about surfing that you love?
I love being
the center of attention...
because it's really
where I should be.
And, uh...
I love the looks
my ladies give me, you know.
The little glint.
I love that.
I love holding the ladies.
You know what I'm talking about?
[INTERVIEWER]
I think so. Sort of.
Come on, come with me.
Put this curtain in myself.
These are my ladies.
This is Jill.
This is my lady, Amy.
Little Suzie.
Briana.
You know why
we call her Briana, right?
[INTERVIEWER CHUCKLES]
No.
Yeah, it's a long story.
Shaniqua.
Helga.
Miss Kitty.
Jeannie.
I dream of...
Theresa.
This is Theresa right here.
[INTERVIEWER] Now,
is Theresa, is that your...
Dirty girl.
This spot?
This spot is for my...
For my special lady, Lia.
I'm gonna say that
one more time.
Lia.
Oh, yeah.
That's a sweet, sweet lady.
[WOMAN] Tank, are you
polishing your trophies again?
I... I...
Mom, I...
I wasn't polishing.
I was talking to my friends.
I'm gonna be polishing later.
[CAMERAMAN] When's he
coming out? I'm gonna run out of film.
[INTERVIEWER]
Hey, hey! There he is.
Mr. Topanga, could you tell us
why you're not dead?
No!
I am dead. I'm dead.
[CODY YELLING]
What are you doing?
Hey, who said you...
Turn the board around.
Get back here.
No, just come out here
and show me some moves.
- No, no, no.
- Come on!
Why not?
Grab a board and come out.
Hey, you wanna kill yourself,
go ahead, fine with me.
Just don't mess up my board.
How do you turn this thing?
It's not a short board.
Sit back on it.
[WHISTLES] Hey, watch the wave!
[GAGGING]
You mess up my board,
I'm messing up your other foot.
Hey, I'm just trying to ride
this, this...
canoe or whatever it is, okay?
Well, stop trying... so hard.
Just relax.
What do you mean rela...
[SCREAMS]
Long, smooth strokes.
Dig deep.
Dig, come on.
I'm digging, I'm digging!
Keep the nose up.
Keep it up. You're...
Watch it, you're pearling.
[GRUNTING]
[LAUGHING]
[GRUNTS]
What are you doing?
Come on, please?
Z, I can't learn anything
with you on the beach, man.
Well, then you're not
gonna learn anything.
Now, come on in.
Z, I'm not coming in
until you come out.
Oh, you're coming in, all right.
He's not even watching the wave.
[INTERVIEWER]
What wave?
That one.
Five, four, three, two and...
[SCREAMS]
[COUGHING]
Don't touch my stuff, man.
I couldn't help it.
I-I just wanted
to learn from the best.
Yeah, well.
I don't surf anymore, okay?
[COUGHS]
What?
What do you mean
you don't surf...
Hey, hey. You wanna learn
how to surf the right way?
Uh... sure.
Then you gotta make
your own board, all right?
Wha... Wait, just what do
you mean you don't sur...
Can't hear ya.
Can I ask one quest...
We're making a board.
[INTERVIEWER] Could
you tell me about your board?
Um...
I just have a, uh...
palm-tree board.
I would have to say it's not
the nicest board in the world,
but it is a pretty good board.
The ancient Hawaiians believe
that "mana", or heart,
was transferred into
the surfboard as you shaped it.
What are your thoughts on that?
What's up with the hair?
Could fit a whole fish in there.
My dream surfboard.
It's pretty powerful.
You can add a lot
of attachments to it,
like a grenade-launcher
attachment.
Anybody know
whose board this is?
[ROB] Pretty sure
it's the chicken's.
Has anybody seen the chicken?
Cody!
I know he's out here.
I can feel it in my nuggets.
[INTERVIEWER] Aren't
you nervous out in the jungle?
It's kind of dangerous.
Dude, the jungle is the most
peaceful place on the planet.
[INTERVIEWER GRUNTS]
All right, hold it steady.
[CODY]
This is a dream come true.
This is a dream come true,
here to be here with Z, doing this.
- And it's koa wood.
- Where's the, uh...
Which all the best boards
are made from koa wood.
All right, now...
I drew this pattern as a guide.
Now, do you wanna have your...
board with a lot of rocker
or just a little?
- Uh...
- Hm.
I don't know.
I guess I'd like...
Oh. What you, what you want
is something in between.
Trust me.
I'm the expert here, okay?
Okay.
So, um...
here are your shaping tools.
Now, remember,
the board's already
inside there, see, somewhere.
And what you're doing...
is you're trying to find it.
- Reveal it. All right?
- Okay.
All right.
Every carve counts.
[SCOFFS]
Why are you smiling?
Don't smile.
I'm not... I'm not smiling.
I'm just, you know, excited.
This isn't like
hacking a piece of ice.
You know, it takes
patience and finesse.
All right already.
I'm trying...
Can you just
give me the tools, please?
- [SIGHS]
- Sheesh.
- All right, here, take it. Go ahead.
- Okay. Thank you.
Here we go.
What are you doing?
- [GROANS]
- [SIGHS]
You, look, if you're
gonna do it, you do it right.
All right, look.
First of all, with the grain.
With the grain.
You see what I'm doing here?
You let the tool...
do the work.
You see?
Just like you're riding a wave.
You let the wave do the work.
You don't fight the wave.
You can't fight
these big waves, Code.
Long strokes.
Loads of finesse.
Find the board within the tree.
Nice and easy.
Yeah, I got it.
See that? You just...
Just...
Maybe I could do it now, okay?
...move with...
With the...
Can I do it now?
Sh...
[WHISPERS]
Can I do it now?
- Yeah, I...
- [CLEARS THROAT]
...got carried away.
Sorry about that.
- It's your board.
- It's my board.
Okay, with the grain.
I got it.
Don't forget to eyeball it.
- I got it.
- Once in a while.
Okay, long strokes,
with the grain.
Not too long.
[SIGHS]
Here we go.
You're doing it wrong, Cody.
- Will you just let me?
- No, Cody, seriously...
I can't... No finesse when
you're in my face. Okay?
Just let me make the board.
Do you want my help?
Do I? No, I don't
want your help.
I don't want your help.
Oh, you don't want my help?
- Oh. All right. Fine.
- Okay?
- Fine.
- I just wanna make my board.
Build the board yourself, man.
All right? Fine.
Thank you. Thank you.
I don't care
what the board looks like.
You're the one
who's gotta ride the thing.
Fine. I'll...
Thank you.
It's in there somewhere.
Go find it.
Gee. Walk over there, please!
Please.
Don't cut yourself.
[SIGHS]
Tsk.
So it's day three, yeah?
I, uh...
I come across Pen Guans.
I'm Chicken Joe. Joseph.
It's long for Joe.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN DIALECT]
Sweet, man.
And, uh, you know,
they treat me as their king
and put me in a hot tub.
[ALL CHANTING]
[JOE] It is, I guess,
their royal hot tub.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
[ALL YIPPING]
[SNEEZES]
[ALL SNEEZE]
[JOE]
Got kind of hot and steamy.
But really opened up my pores,
you know?
It was kind of cool.
They kind of served me food
while I was in there.
It was like dinner and a show.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN DIALECT]
Yum-yum-yum-yum-yum.
[LAUGHS]
Yum-yum-yum.
Oh, yum-yum.
Yum-yum-yum-yum!
[ALL]
♪ Yum-yum-yum ♪
♪ Yum-yum-yum-yum-yum ♪
- ♪ Hey! ♪
- Whoo!
As enjoyable as it was,
I still had a vision
of my quest.
Okay, thank you.
See you guys later.
I-I gotta get going.
[ALL CLAMORING]
[INTERVIEWER GRUNTS]
Not again.
You know what else it was?
Look, okay, I had the board.
The board was fine.
The board was great.
[GRUNTING]
- Huh?
- How's it going?
What?
No, it's going great, man.
It's great.
[INTERVIEWER]
It did look a little rough.
A little rough?
The board looked a little...
It's a work in progress, bro.
You think it's good enough
for the big waves?
I-I think it's good enough
for any wave.
Ah. Oh, oh.
Uh, hang on.
Okay, let's say
I'm a big wave, you know?
Hold on.
No, no, no, no.
- Hey, hey, hey, where you...
- Hold on!
Where you goin'?
It's my board, man, all right?
Why don't you take your board
and go try it out?
- That's what I'm... Maybe I will, huh?
- Good.
Piece of junk. Watch!
[BIG Z]
Oh, that was...
Nice ride, man.
Nice ride.
[GRUNTS]
You know, this is
supposed to be fun.
Look, I got three days
until the contest.
I don't have time for fun.
Oh, no time for fun, huh?
Hey, Cody!
What?
Bring me some clams
when you come back!
I'm not coming back!
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, he'll be back.
No, I won't!
Eh, he'll be back.
Hey, you guys like barbecue?
- [CAMERAMAN] Yeah, sure.
- [INTERVIEWER] Yeah.
Got some wood here.
I wasted my whole day,
and I have nothing
to show for it, which is...
[BOTH YELP]
- [SIGHS]
- Oh.
Lani.
Uh, I was just actually
going to check on you.
- That's why you were... Oh. Yeah, no.
- And the Geek.
- Listen.
- What?
The Geek, Geek is Big Z.
What? I know.
You know?
- How'd you find out?
- We went to the beach.
- You got him down to the beach?
- Yeah.
Well, I've been trying to get Z
out of that tree for ten years,
and you got him all the way
down to the beach in one day?
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah.
This is fantastic!
Woo-hoo!
- [GRUNTS]
- [LAUGHS]
It's amazing!
So, so...
Do you wanna go somewhere fun?
- Uh...
- Do you wanna go somewhere really, really fun?
- Uh, oh...
- Unless you want...
I mean, did you wanna
get back to Big Z?
- I'm sorry, I shouldn't have invited you.
- No, no, no, no, no.
- What? Okay. No?
- No, look, I...
- I wanna have fun.
- Oh, okay.
Do I need, like,
mints or something?
- [LAUGHS]
- You tell me.
- [LANI] No, you won't need mints.
- [CODY] Okay, all right.
[LANI] Z used to carry us up
here on his shoulders, and we'd,
we'd have so much fun.
It's one of
my favorite spots on Pen Gu.
Really?
Boy, to be
eight years old again.
What is this?
Well, you don't wanna
get all cut up, do you?
No, no. What... Hold on.
What are you doing?
No, no, no, no.
I'm outta here.
I'm better off...
- [SCREAMING]
- [LANI] Whooo!
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
[CODY]
No, no, no, no.
Oh, whoa! Whoa!
- Oh!
- Whoo-hoo!
It's going down! No, no, no!
Whoa, whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
This is insane!
Stop fighting it, Cody!
Just let go!
[LANI]
All right!
[CODY]
Whoa!
Whoo-hoo!
Oh, now I'm in front of you now.
[CODY]
What's going on now?
[LANI]
It's not a race!
[CODY]
Whoo-hoo!
Okay, wait, don't take
the left... Cody!
No!
[CODY]
Whoo! Yeah!
[LAUGHS]
Give up, slowpoke!
It's over with now!
Not for long!
Give up now, sucker!
[LAUGHS]
I beat you!
Congratulations, you sure did.
You should probably
get out of there.
Why is that? This stuff is...
Look at me. It's so beautiful.
Look at it.
What is this stuff?
- See those things up above you?
- Uh-huh.
- Um, they're glowworms.
- Right.
So...
you're right beneath them.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, that's poop.
- [GRUNTS]
- [LAUGHING]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[LANI] You know
how some stinks stink,
and other stinks smell good?
- Yeah.
- This is like a good stink.
[SCOFFS]
A good stink?
Can I tell you
something personal?
We're in the shower together.
You can say whatever you want.
I'm serious.
I'm really, really,
really jealous of you.
[SCOFFS]
Why?
I couldn't get Z off his butt
for the last ten years,
and then you come along, and...
He must really think
a lot of you.
I don't know.
I mean, I've been a jerk to him,
so I don't know what he thinks.
No, you haven't.
I have.
I've been a jerk to him.
Well, then go...
not be a jerk.
What does it matter to you,
anyways?
He's my uncle.
He's the only family I've got.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Okay.
[REGGAE SONG PLAYING]
[SNORING]
[GRUNTS]
- [SPLAT]
- [GASPS]
Hm.
Z? No.
No. No, no, no.
Don't, don't you do it.
Z, don't do it. No.
- No.
- Let's see here.
I swear, man,
if you break that board...
- It's stronger than I thought.
- If you break it...
Should've been broken by now.
Come on, man!
Come on!
[LAUGHING]
Oh, look at that.
Ah, that's the best place
in the world to be, in the tube.
Really?
Aw, yeah,
better than winning.
The trophy, all that stuff.
[PENGUIN 1]
Tube riding is,
is the ultimate,
ultimate thing in surfing.
To ride inside the wave and,
and make it out of it.
It's all what we want to do
everyday.
[PENGUIN 2] Ah, it's, it's
almost impossible to describe.
There's nothing
I can compare it to.
[PENGUIN 3] It's a
feeling that, um, you know,
you know not too many people
will experience, and, uh,
and, uh, so it's special
in that sense.
[PENGUIN 4] And then
you just try to remember it.
You're like, "Geez, I wish
I could remember that,"
or "I wish I could get
that again."
It's just so addicting.
Ah, once you get inside,
you never wanna get out.
Wow.
- That's amazing.
- Oh, yeah, man.
Nothing like it.
Okay, so that aside,
well, I mean,
how many points
would you get for getting tube?
Like what does it depend on
for the contest?
Points?
[SIGHS]
What?
Do you know, you know
who you sound like right now?
I promote happiness!
Can you see the happiness
emanating from me?
What's wrong with you?
- [INTERVIEWER] Mr. Belafonte?
- [CAMERAMAN] We're live.
Huh? Oh, good. Good.
I have to say...
I have no doubt
that this year's Big Z Memorial
is gonna be just the best ever.
[HAWAIIAN MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
[SAL] With the competition
just one day away,
the excitement is definitely
building here on Pen Gu Island.
[VIDEO FAST FORWARDING]
[SNORES]
[BURPS]
[HAWAIIAN SONG PLAYS
IN FAST FORWARD]
[AUDIO SQUEAKING]
Oh, that didn't take too long.
I feel lightheaded.
So get this.
On my search for Cody,
I bump into
my hot-tub buddies again.
[ALL SPEAKING FOREIGN DIALECT]
Oh, I get it.
You guys look hungry.
Yeah, yeah. You've probably
got the munchies or something.
Uno momento.
Squidito on el stickito?
[ALL GASPS]
- [SNIFFS]
- Mmm? Mmm?
[SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[ALL CHEERING]
Whoa, check it out.
Dude, dude, have you seen
my friend, Cody?
You know, he's kind of
like a penguin.
Um...
He's got a lot of black on him,
a lot of white.
[LAUGHING]
Yum-yum-yum!
[INTERVIEWER] Hey, guys,
how'd you learn how to surf?
I saw Big Z do it, actually.
I don't think you were born yet.
- I wasn't?
- No, I don't think so.
Lani?
I like her when she
teaches us because...
[SNIFFS]
Smudge!
Not another one!
I think he really has to go
to the bathroom right now.
Okay, so, what's next?
The board is done.
What're we doing?
- The board is done?
- The board is done.
Oh, well, uh...
Let's do some training.
What do you say?
Finally!
[INTERVIEWER]
Can we get a shot of you...
No, you gotta get a
long shot, boys. All right.
Hey, Z, come on! Hey.
Where you goin'?
Oh, I thought you said
we were gonna train.
Not in the water.
Jeez, what're you thinking?
- You wanna surf like, uh, Big Z used to, right?
- Yeah.
I've got some tests here
to figure out your potential.
Let's do it.
No, no, no.
Put them on your eyes.
Like this. Yeah.
On my eyes.
[SNICKERS]
Take it, Cody.
Can we do some training,
seriously, please?
What're you talking about?
What do you think we're doing?
We're acting like a bunch of
nutjobs. That's what I think we're doing.
Yeah, good.
You're learning!
[SHRIEKS]
[BIG Z]
And a big set comes in.
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHS]
Wipeout!
That's it.
- Take it easy.
- That's insane!
This is getting ridiculous.
- You having fun?
- I hate you.
[IMITATES WATER SPLASHING]
Big, you know, slow...
Yoo-hoo!
And he does this flip
over the top.
All right, now you go.
Look, and...
Ooh, whoo.
No joy, man. No joy.
Failed.
Whew. I'm starting
to see it, man.
Z, I think I know
what you're talking about.
[MEN LAUGHING]
Oh, well, this...
That's great.
[CAMERAMAN]
Sorry, man.
As long as we're all
having fun, right?
Z, wake up. Wake up, Z.
[MUMBLES]
Z!
[SNORING]
Hey, Z, breakfast!
[GRUNTS]
Not a chance.
Four...
You gotta get up earlier
in the morning.
three, two...
[YELPS]
one.
[CODY LAUGHING]
That is fun. That...
- Oh, you're having fun, huh?
- I am. Yes. Now I am.
Oh.
Oh, well, then, Cody,
you passed!
- What?
- You did it! You're ready!
Let's surf! Come on!
Z, don't play with me, Z.
- We're surfing?
- Whoo-hoo!
Yes! Yes!
[LAUGHING]
Okay.
[UPBEAT SONG PLAYING]
Yeah.
Hey, check it... Oh!
[LAUGHS]
Hey, I didn't know
you could surf!
- Wh-wh-wh-whoa.
- Relax.
Long, slow, smooth.
- Like making the board!
- There you go.
- All right. Okay.
- Feels good, yeah?
Yeah!
[BIG Z AND CODY]
Lani!
You're in the water, Z!
[BIG Z] Come on out.
Get wet! Come on!
Lani...
thank you.
[CODY]
Whoo!
Look at that!
[LAUGHS]
[SONG CONTINUES]
- Whoo! Great ride!
- Nice! That's it!
[BIG Z]
Nice job.
- Big Z is back!
- Whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
[SIGHS]
This is what it's all about.
What could be better than this?
[PLAYS CHEERFUL MELODY]
♪ Hey, it's impossible ♪
♪ To be down ♪
Oh, jeez.
[SCOFFS]
♪ When you're playing ♪
♪ A uke ♪
[HIGH VOICE]
I need some help, Lani,
on this landing
for the high note.
[ALL]
♪ Ooh ♪
Yay! Nice. Nice.
[ALL LAUGH]
Is that the only song
that you know?
Pretty much.
You wanna here it again?
- [BOTH] No, no, no.
- It goes like this...
No? No, okay.
Got you there, didn't I?
I must say you were
quite amazing out there today.
You weren't
so bad yourself, kiddo.
Thanks to this guy.
Nah, I just pointed you
in a direction.
Question, Z.
[BIG Z]
Hm?
You changed your mind
about the song.
No, no, no.
No, no.
I got it. Here it goes.
Something like this.
I was wondering if you'd come
watch me ride tomorrow.
- ♪ This ukelele ♪
- Z!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We'll both ride, man.
No, no, no. Not just...
In the contest.
Contest? What contest?
The Big Z Memorial.
You remember that one?
I mean, I know,
I know I'm asking a lot,
- but it would really, really be...
- [SIGHS]
the biggest thing
in the world to me
if you could come.
I mean...
You still wanna be a part
of all that?
Absolutely.
Well, what do you
want me there for, anyway?
I know, I thought maybe
you'd wanna be there.
I mean, I don't know
why it's a big deal.
It's no big deal.
[SIGHS]
Why won't you come?
[CHUCKLES]
I'm not coming.
Why?
- Just give, give it a rest.
- It's getting cold, guys.
Can you tell me
why you're hiding.
- Hiding?
- Why are you hiding?
[LANI]
I'll have to eat this by myself.
Why didn't you come back
after you fell off the wave?
That wave.
[SIGHS]
[BIG Z]
That last day,
winning...
had become everything to me.
I knew I was gonna beat Tank.
But then, uh, you know,
he starts to...
surf circles around me.
I saw what he was doing.
I couldn't do what he was doing.
Times had changed,
you know. He...
[SIGHS]
I didn't wanna walk back
on that beach
with all my fans there,
you know.
A loser. Everyone
looking at Big Z, the...
The loser, the has-been.
So...
[SIGHS]
Poof.
Big Z's dead,
and that's how it's gonna stay.
Let me play you that song.
[PLAYING CHEERFUL MELODY]
Wha... What about
"never give up"?
[SIGHS]
What about "find a way"?
Yeah, well...
You're giving up, Z.
You're giving up.
Yeah. I'm giving up.
That's my way.
[SCOFFS]
Giving up.
I thought you were the one guy.
You don't like it,
find your own way.
Leave me out of it.
Z!
[SLOW SONG PLAYING]
[GRUNTS]
[CODY]
I messed up. I'm just...
I'm... not good.
This is when I needed someone.
I needed him.
You know, it's...
I mean, if...
It's hard enough
losing one dad, but...
- [INTERVIEWER] What do you mean by that?
- Nothing.
Nothing, man. Forget it.
[SCREAMS]
Oh! Whoa, whoa!
[ALL CLAMORING]
Peaceful, peaceful.
I'm in peace. I come in peace.
- Cody!
- Joe!
[SIGHS] I've been
looking everywhere for you.
Really? You've been
looking for me?
Dude, I didn't lose you
on the whale.
I'm not gonna lose you now.
Thank you.
Seriously, thank you.
- [PEN GUAN] Yum-yum.
- Radical.
- [HORN BLARES]
- [GASPS]
Oh, they're, they're starting.
Cody, we gotta go!
Come on!
Wait a minute. Joe? Joe?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Watch this, dude.
I can speak their language.
Mondo cudo pungu.
[YELLS]
Dude, I totally need my board.
I don't even know where
it is. I gotta go find it.
I'll see you in the lineup then.
See you, Joe.
[JOE] This is gonna
be fun, huh? Whoo.
[PEN GUAN]
See ya!
[SAL] The tenth annual Big Z
is about to get underway,
and, whoa,
it is the day of days.
Big mountainous bombs
marching into our coastline.
Kelly Slater, on a danger level,
one to ten, give me a number.
Twenty.
Wow. Rob?
Oh, there'll be blood.
I'm scared,
and I'm in the booth!
What're you doing here?
- Mike.
- You're gonna kill yourself.
Please don't do this
to yourself. Please.
Look what happened last time.
Look...
- Agh!
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Good to see you back.
- Are you serious?
You know, you're gonna be
a real crowd pleaser.
I'm telling ya.
These people
are gonna eat you up.
I'll be expecting big things
from you.
Thank you.
[REGGIE OVER MEGAPHONE] Hey, people,
big announcement, Cody Maverick, he's back.
The Wipeout King is back.
And I'm gonna tell you,
start looking for the sharks.
They'll be circling 'cause
there'll be blood in the water.
Spectacular carnage today.
Thank you.
Reggie Belafonte. Hey.
Little guy, big hair, big
thoughts, big heart. Come on.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Oh-ho-ho.
Look at this.
You're goin' down, snowflake.
I'm gonna make you wish
you were never even hatched.
You wanna see my trophies?
[HORN BLARES]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Whoo!
[PANTING]
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Arnold, no.
[GROANS]
Yeah!
[SAL] About 24 surfers
battling their way out to the...
Ooh! Good golly.
Make that 18.
Rob, after such a heavy wipeout
earlier in the week,
what do you think is going
through Maverick's mind?
[ROB] He's gonna have
to stay focused
and channel that energy
into good places.
When are you gonna get a life?
[PANTING]
You are a nobody.
You should've stayed
in Antarctica, kid.
[GRUNTS]
Whoa!
[PANTING]
Cody, Cody, Cody!
Whoo!
Oh, he made it! He...
That... Yeah, good.
[SAL] What an amazing first
ride mind-blower from Maverick.
[CHUCKLES]
Did you guys see that?
Oh, man, I...
You know, I...
I thought I was gonna lose it,
then I just...
Whew. I just let go, you know.
You know, I let go,
and there it was.
[UPBEAT THEME PLAYING]
[SAL]
Wow, it's been an amazing day
of shredding in
less than stellar conditions,
but I never would've guessed
our three finalists.
Well, Sal, it's no surprise
that Tank Evans
has just breezed his way
into the finals.
[KELLY]
And Cody Maverick,
from a horrible wipeout
a few days ago to this.
[ROB] And Chicken Joe from
Sheboygan. Who would've guessed it?
[SAL IN SING SONG VOICE]
I have never
seen a finals like this.
We're in the finals, Joe.
No way! We get
to surf some more?
- Isn't it exciting?
- Yeah.
Look at that. Ha-ha!
- Huh?
- This is great, huh?
Hey, you know,
you should know this,
Tank loves you.
Looks like this'll be
the easiest year ever.
[LAUGHS]
Oh, no way.
Cody, did you hear that?
It's gonna be easy.
[CHUCKLES]
Are you loving this?
[ALL CHEERING]
Yeah!
[INTERVIEWER] So who would
you like to see win the trophy?
It's not so important to me.
- [HICCUPS] - Friends are
better than anything in the world.
Friends are forever.
Trophies, never know
what they can have ha...
- [HICCUPS]
- Happen to them.
[HICCUPS]
- That was awesome, mate.
- Thank you, man.
Muy impressivo, my friend.
Thank you, bro.
Thank you.
- Wow. Finals.
- Hey!
Yeah. No, I know.
It's... I can't even...
I know, I think I can win
this thing, it's just...
It's too much right now,
you know.
Yeah, well,
that's all you came for.
What?
What was that supposed to mean?
You made it
pretty clear last night
that winning's more important
to you than Z or me.
- Lani, that's not...
- But hey,
maybe you'll get to take
your stupid trophy home.
- Lani, come on.
- Come here, you!
[CAMERAS CLICKING]
How about this, huh?
Lemme tell you something.
You win this thing,
you and me, we're going places.
Huh? Hey!
Look at this kid.
- [ALL CHEERING]
- He is a champ.
[HORN BLARES]
[PENGUIN] Chicken Joe,
you're the bro. Woo-hoo!
Tank, nine-time
defending champion.
He will roll on you.
[KELLY] Expecting him
to win this thing, Sal.
It's basically a contest
for second place.
First, I'm gonna take you down.
Then I'm gonna fry the chicken.
- [JOE GASPS]
- What?
That cloud looks
just like a kitten.
Aw.
[HORN BLARES]
[ROCK SONG PLAYING]
[SAL]
Maverick and Evans take off.
Mine!
And it's Evans droppin' in!
[GRUNTS]
And Tank's playing games,
blocking Maverick's every move.
[YELPING]
But Maverick sticks a rail!
Tank Evans down!
[SCREAMS]
I have never,
ever seen this before!
[ALL GASPS]
[ALL CHEERING]
But I'd love to see it again.
Cody trying
to take back the wave
that Tank snaked from him.
Evans toying with him,
not paying attention.
And there's the outside rail.
Evans goes down.
And it's Maverick
with this new-school move.
We'll call it The Maverick.
[SPITS]
[YELLS]
And look at this.
Maverick scoring big.
Oh, it's so cute.
It's got the little paws
and the whiskers.
Whoa.
Chicken Joe
with a no-paddle drop-in! Ha!
[IMITATES MOTOR REVVING]
Here we go!
Nobody needs
to help this chicken.
Woo-hoo!
I'm flying!
- [ALL CHEERING]
- Alakazoo!
Maverick and Joe tied,
and no score for Tank Evans?
Unbelievable.
[SAL] Surfers,
this is your final wave!
Joe, man, this is it.
This wave wins it, huh?
Yeah, man!
Whoo!
[SAL] This wave is stacking up
to be a beautiful tube.
Maverick should score big
on this one!
[TANK ROARING]
[SAL]
But wait! Evans drops in.
[GASPS]
It looks like Evans
is gonna take out the chicken.
[SAL]
What's Maverick doing?
Go, Joe, go!
Got it! Let's go!
[SAL]
I don't believe this.
This contest
was Maverick's to win.
And now Evans pushing Maverick
out of bounds
and into The Boneyards.
Whoa!
[COUGHS]
[GRUNTING]
[ALL GASPING]
Whoa!
[GASPS]
Tank, look out!
You look out!
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHS]
[SCREAMS]
[CROWD MURMURING]
[GRUNTS]
[PANTING]
[GASPS]
[GRUNTING]
[YELPS]
Code!
Z!
[GRUNTS]
Cody, come on.
- Z!
- Paddle! Come on!
Dig faster!
Come on, dig! Dig!
Don't dig. Don't dig.
What?
Let the wave carry you, Cody!
Z!
You're gonna have to time it!
You're gonna come right here,
right to me!
[GRUNTS]
Five, four...
Three, two, one.
Z!
[GRUNTS]
Wha... Where's Cody?
[SIGHS]
[CROWD MURMURING]
Don't touch it!
Don't touch that!
This is a reminder
of the young surfer
who gave his life
for the sport he loved.
[BOTH PANTING]
Ah, there you are.
[BOTH GRUNT]
[PANTING]
I can't believe it!
I can't believe it.
You came back.
You saved my life, man.
Thank you, man.
Thank you.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Come on, come on, come on.
You're gonna tip us.
[SIGHS]
Well...
I lost.
Yeah.
Me too.
[CHUCKLES]
Come on.
Let's go, loser.
You wanna help me out here?
You know the routine.
Come on.
- Long. Yeah, that's it.
- Smooth strokes.
Smooth, you know.
Come on.
[REGGIE] Young Joey
MacEnroe was a beacon
for a new generation.
- May he rest in peace.
- [SOBBING]
So, what are my bids
for the board?
Who'll give me 30? Thirty,
give me 30, come on. Thirty.
Don't touch his stuff, man.
- Pal, if you wanna bid...
- Gimme that.
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Um...
[GASPS]
[CROWD MURMURING]
Hey. Hey, everyone.
Heh, how you been?
- Oh, my gosh!
- Oh...
Yeah.
[PENGUIN]
Hey, man, that's Z!
That's me.
Skank, what's happening, man?
Got a little sand
in your egg sack there, fella.
[CROWD LAUGHS]
Where have you been,
Z? What happened?
Oh, you know...
I, uh, I got lost
for a little while.
Uh, but, uh, that kid,
that kid there, Cody...
he, uh, He pointed the way back.
[FOOTSTEPS PATTERING]
[MOANS]
Cody, Cody, Cody, Cody, Cody!
[TEARFULLY] Could you please shut that
off? You know, could you give me a minute?
Hey, hey! Check it out!
How about this?
You wanna talk
about talent scout?
People find talent.
I bring 'em back from the dead.
The now living legend...
Reggie, Reggie, shut...
- Ladies and...
- Shut up.
- What? Shut up? What?
- I'm not a legend.
I'm just a guy
looking for some nice waves,
some good friends.
- Ow! Hello.
- Hey, guys,
the swell is happening
over on the north shore!
[CROWD APPLAUDS]
- I'm right behind you, Z.
- Ouch, that, that hurt.
[PENGUIN]
Gimme a hand with this.
Hey, come back here!
[ARNOLD]
We love you, Z!
You don't just walk away!
Come on!
Folks, it looks like he's
taking this loss pretty hard.
- [SNIFFLING] - Tank, how
does it feel to lose after nine time...
I wasn't kissing her.
You can't have her!
[KIDS CLAMORING]
[SCREAMS]
Guys, guys.
Can we get a few words?
- Hey.
- Oh, hey, Rob.
So you gave up the trophy
to help Joe, man.
What's that about?
Well, you know, Rob,
that's, uh...
- That's what friends do.
- Yeah.
How's it feel to win, Joe?
I won?
Come on!
I'll tell my mom.
Gimme, gimme, gimme!
[TANK SCREAMS]
Oops.
Oh, Lia! Oh. Oh, uh...
Oh, Lia.
Don't you walk away from me!
I am Reggie Belafon...
[WIG RIPS]
Oh! Turn that thing off.
Mikey! You are so fired!
I can't imagine a better day!
[UPBEAT SONG PLAYING]
[CODY]
Dude, this,
I mean, this whole experience
has just been...
It's amazing. Z?
I don't think I've ever had a
better friend to me in my life.
- It's just really cool to have everything I need.
- Whoo-hoo!
- Don't do it!
- Help!
Oh, Arnold!
To be honest, man,
I'm kind of, like,
bored of talking
about myself, so...
Is that cool?
You guys got what you need?
[INTERVIEWER]
Yeah. Yeah, we got it.
All right. Be good.
Hey!
[PEN GUANS CHEERING]
[MIKE]
Cowabunga!
[LAUGHING]
[SONG CONTINUES]
[REGGAE SONG PLAYING]
Oh, of course
we're proud of him.
I mean, what mother
wouldn't be proud of him?
We're so full of proudness.
You know what?
He followed his dream,
and he went out there,
and now he's coming home
with the trophy.
I mean, I can't wait
to see the trophy.
[INTERVIEWER] Well,
there's not really a trophy.
Oh, is there like a big shell
or something like that?
There's no shell.
There's no trophy.
- He didn't...
- What is there?
- Well, he didn't win.
- [CHUCKLES] What?
How bad, how bad was it?
I mean, did he get smoked?
Well, he was in the finals.
He was in the finals.
Second place?
Yeah, that's losing.
Winning is not everything, Glen.
- Right.
- I mean, look at...
- Look at what Cody did...
- Wait, wait.
Go back to the "winning
isn't everything" thing.
That doesn't compute, really.
You know what, Glen?
I really hope that someday
you can be more like Cody.
This interview's over.
[REGGAE SONG CONTINUES]
[SONG CONTINUES]
[ROCK 'N' ROLL MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
[POP SONG PLAYING]
[SONG CONTINUES]
[UKULELE PLAYING
CHEERFUL MELODY]
[BIG Z] You know, I think
it's actually called an,
An "ook" I think
is the proper pronunciation.
It's important.
Little island, uh,
north of here.
"Ha-va-ii" or something
like that.
Always wanted to go.
Big waves bigtime.
Yeah.
Ook, ook.
I think. I think it's "ook."
Anyway, here we go.
You ready?
All right, join in if you think
you can do this.
Remember when we were
talking about you leaving?
That was great. Remember when
you were gonna go? Remember that?
[INTERVIEWER]
We're gonna go, but...
Yeah, you should still go.
It's technical equipment.
I know what I'm doing.
I can unplug one of your
little Hollywood devices.
- Please, don't touch that.
- The lighting thing.
- [EDNA] Glen!
- Whatever you call that. And then the microphone thing.
- I'm sorry.
- It's easy.
Go back to Hollywood.
[EDNA] Glen, Cody
would never do this.